Guide to the Patrick Knight Papers WAG.179
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Patrick Knight Papers
1949-1980
1960-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Social Service Employees Union. Local 371
Knight, Patrick
WAG.179
12 Linear Feet in 12 record cartons
Patrick Knight served as president of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, from 1974 to 1976. The union primarily represents New York City workers in the social service professions. The collection contains files related to the activities of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, primarily during the 1970s. A large potion of the papers focus on Local 371's legislative advocacy and its support of Local 420's Health and Hospitals Corporation strike.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.059 is associated with this collection.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains files related to the activities of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, primarily during the 1970s. A large potion of the papers focus on Local 371's legislative advocacy and its support of Local 420's Health and Hospitals Corporation strike. Christian and/or anti-Coummunist publications obtained by Knight through subscriptions and Local 371 correspondence also make up a significant part of the collection. To a lesser extent, there are also publications from a number of civil rights organizations.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Researchers interested in the Social Service Employees Union, Local 371 of AFSCME may also wish to consult the following collections:
Social Service Employees Union Records (WAG 003)
Social Service Employees Union Photographs (PHOTOS 014)
Christopher Rhoades Dykema Papers (WAG 016)
Michael Padwee Papers (WAG 004)
Social Service Employees Union, Local 371 Audio (OH 063)
Researchers interested in Local 420 may also wish to consult AFSCME, Local 420 (Hospital Workers) Records (WAG 215) and AFSCME, Local 420 (Hospital Workers) Photographs (PHOTOS 212).
Historical/Biographical Note
Patrick Knight served as president of the Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), Local 371, from 1974 to 1976. SSEU Local 371 is part of District Council 37 of the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), AFL-CIO. The union primarily represents New York City workers in the social service professions. During Knight's tenure as president, Local 371 was particularly focused on reintegrating Income Maintenance programs with social service programs within the Human Resources Administration of the City of New York (the programs became separated in 1970). Knight was also the Secretary-Treasurer of Local 371 from 1970 to 1974. He was active in politics outside of his political involvement on behalf of SSEU, serving as a delegate to Wisconsin Democratic Conventions in the 1950s and 1960s.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Civil rights -- United States.; Labor unions |x Political activity |x Law and legislation.; Anti-communist movements -- United States.; Municipal officials and employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; AFSCME. Local 420 (Municipal Hospital Workers Union) (New York, N.Y.); AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.); Social Service Employees Union. Local 371; Knight, Patrick
- The Freedom School Newsletter and Other Freedom School and Rampant College Publications; Political Campaigns Promotional Materials; Correspondence and Publications on Communism as a Threat to Public Education and National Security; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee and Students for a Democratic Society Reports; and Publications on South Vietnam and the National Liberation Front., 1962-circa 1973 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with and Publications of Conservative and Christian Book Stores; Human Events and Operation Yorkville Newsletters; and Publications from Conservative Organizations such as Fighting Homefolks of Fighting Men and Liberty Lobby., 1954-circa 1964 (Box 2)
- The White Sentinel Newsletters; National States' Rights Party; Liberation Committee for Africa; Liberty Amendment Promotional Material; and Publications from Conservative and/or Christian Organizations., 1957-circa 1963 (Box 3)
- Academic Papers and Syllabi from Wisconsin State College Sociology Department; Student Newspapers and Publications; National Unemployment Estimates; Gerald Knight Correspondence with Potential Employers; Manuscript "Concepts of Bohemianism in American Thought, 1890-1930" by John R. Frisch; and Publications of and Correspondence with Christian and/or Anti-Communist Organizations., 1949-circa 1963 (Box 4)
- Christian and/or Anti-Communist Publications from Organizations such as Citizens Action Committee and Christian Crusade; House Committee on Un-American Activities Reports; Committee of One Million Against the Admission of Communist China to the United Nations Publications and Promotional Materials; Citizens Foreign Aid Committee/The Taxpayers Committee to End Foreign Aid Correspondence and Bulletins; and Freedom Club Bulletin, Christopher News Notes, and Footprints in Time (Christianity Today)., circa 1959-circa 1968 (Box 5)
- Organizational Publications Promoting Free Enterprise and Cooperation Between International Businesses and Political Leaders; Citizens Research Council of Michigan Correspondence and Publications; Publications of and Correspondence With Christian Organizations; and Chicago Teachers Union Publications., 1954-circa 1963 (Box 6)
- Students for a Democratic Society Publications and Conference Papers; Advocacy Against the House Committee on Un-American Activities; and Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee Press and Publications., circa 1961-1966 (Box 7)
- The South African Observer Newsletters, Minutemen and American Freedom Rallies Information and Form Letters, Ministry Chapel (Hollywood, CA Church Newsletter) and Information and Correspondence from Other Christian Organizations; College Right-Wing Political Advocacy and Publications; Operation Information News Letter, International Peasant Union Newsletters, and Information on Various Anti-Communist Organizations., circa 1961-circa 1967 (Box 8)
- Students for a Democratic Society Publications on Economic Research; Civil Rights Publications from Collegiate Groups and at National Level; Anti-Vietnam War Advocacy; and Promotional Papers and Ephemera from Democratic Political Campaigns (1950s and 1960s)., 1957-1971 (Box 9)
- Social Service Employees Union (SSEU) Local 371-- Election Materials (1980); Minutes; American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) Correspondence; Election Results; Support for United Farm Workers and Local 420 Health and Hospitals Corporation Strike; Office of Collective Bargaining Disputes with City of New York; and Memos and Correspondence with New York State and Federal Governments Regarding Support of Re-Integration Bill (Assembly Bill 3949A)., 1959-1980 (Box 10)
- Social Service Employees Union (SSEU) Local 371-- Memos; Administrative Papers; AFSCME District 37 and Local 420 Information; Municipal Credit Union Concerns; and Correspondence and Information on Support for the Reorganization of Income Maintenance Centers in New York City Department of Social Services., circa 1974-1980 (Box 11)
- Saturday Evening Post, Magazine from Germany (Berliner Illustrirte), Two Magazines from Cuba (INRA), State of Wisconsin Bureau of Civil Defense Communications Flow Chart, Re-Elect Senator Proxmire Poster, John F. Kennedy Sponge, and Nametags and Ribbons of Patrick Knight as Delegate to Wisconsin Democratic Conventions., circa 1960-circa 1964 (Box 12)